okay got Ben Bruno here he's going over
his top four favorite landmine exercises
we went over the single leg RDL we went
over the reverse lunge and now Ben is
going to go over
squats I'd like to go over two ways to
land mine squat this is one of my
favorite squatting variations it's
actually very similar to the goblet
squat which is often used as a teaching
tool I like this because it's similar to
the goblet squat but slightly better in
my opinion because here you can utilize
the mar of the bar to encourage more of
a posterior loation which is a problem a
lot of people have when squatting the
other obvious thing is that there's a
lot more loading potential uh you could
Pro you could go up to 2 300 lb here
whereas a a goblet squat you're limited
by the dumbbells and kettle bells in
your gym so the first squatting
variation is a front loed uh landmine
squat um what that's going to look like
I want to go over how to get the bar
into place because that's going to be
the biggest challenge for people uh
right out of the gate and especially as
you're using heavier weight because with
this weight you can just lift it up like
this but when it gets heavy you can't do
that and you don't want to get hurt so
I'm really anal with the little things
what I want you to do is set up with the
bar right between your legs feed out
squat stance maybe even slightly wi just
getting into position chest up bend down
and use the legs not like this you're
going to hold under the bar and then
just come fast and pop it up here you're
going to hold the bar right at the end
can symmetrical not staggered like that
because that causes you to be imbalanced
through your shoulders and hips so
you're going to get nice and symmetrical
with the bar touching your body one
thing you're going to need to play
around with is your foot position so
some people based on their femur length
are going to with short femur will be
able to stand closer under the bar some
people especially taller lifters and
people with long hamur are going to have
to back up a little but the main thing
is you want to start with the bar
touching your chest you're going to have
to kind of play around with your ideal
foot position but it'll just take a
refer to but what you're going to do
same squat St toes slightly out bar here
elbows pinned here not out to the side
if you're chicken wing it's going to be
really hard to hold heavy weight so I
want you to get nice and tight chest up
as you squat that bar is aring back so
you actually can't fall forward cuz
you'll Jam your chest to little bar so
you're going to go nice chest up
squat here elbows your elbows don't have
to touch your knees but if you can
that's a good idea gives you an idea
that you went all the way down here back
up all the way through and squeeze your
butt so
here squeeze your butt one thing that
you'll see a lot of people screw up is
starting with the weight away from their
body body that's it because it feels
comfortable at the start but what
happens if you notice is when you try to
squat like that the weight comes forward
it's a lot of stress on the upper back
and you're going to round your upper
back and turn around your lower back and
come forward it also puts a lot of the
pressure on your arms and because your
arms aren't nearly as strong as your
legs you're going to limit the loading
so start in nice and
close
down and up now the second way to squat
will be a very similar movement or
rather than loading up top on your chest
you're going to interlock your hands
like this or overlap but not
stagger same starting position that you
use to get the weight into position I
like to interlock chest up here then
shimmy into place so the bar is right in
front of your private going to go here
chest up knees out
like
that I like this for
people that struggle to get to a squat
like this um either because of upper
body weakness or uh I just find that
most women actually do better with this
version it's more comfortable
and in advantage of this over holding a
kettle bell or something similar would
be grip strength because when you
interlock your fingers you get strength
and you don't you're not limited by what
weight you can so that will be a way to
squat I also use this for people that
have lower back pin it's a l l straing
on the on the back
so
here so first version is up here second
version is down here both are great give
them a try